A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Decorations, SG 19.1 FA1779
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation records, Decorations, SG 19.1
1921-1998
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller Foundation
FA1779
30 Cubic Feet
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of awards, memorabilia, artwork, certificates, plaques and other objects.
Arrangement
Arranged primarily by a alphanumeric number that was arbitrarily assigned to each object as the material was received by the Foundation.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of of RAC.
- Rockefeller Foundation Decorations, 1921-1998; 19.1
  Scope and Contents
  This collection consists of awards, memorabilia, artwork, certificates, plaques and other objects.
  Arrangement
  Arranged primarily by a alphanumeric number that was arbitrarily assigned to each object as the material was received by the Foundation.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
  - D61b: Scroll, parchment, 1956 July 26; 12.5 x 17; Crinkled (Box 1, Object 8000)
    General note
    Citation
  - D66: Certificate of commendation: Written in Korean and English, 1957 October 9; Mounted; 14 x 19 (Box 1, Object 8001)
  - D65c: Scroll: Written in Modern Greek with translation, 1956 September 9; Mounted; 11 X 17 (Box 1, Object 8002)
  - D59: Diploma of honor: Written in Turkish, 1955 April 29; Mounted; 13.5 X 16.5 (Box 1, Object 8003)
  - D99: Certificate: Trustees of the Rockefeller Foundation 50th Anniversary, 1963 April 30; Mounted; 11 x 16 (Box 1, Object 8004)
  - D35: Certificate of decoration: El Presidente De la Republica De Cuba; Written in Spanish, 1944 December 3; 11 x 16 (Box 1, Object 8005)
  - D44a: Certificate, parchment: The Minister of State; Written in Spanish with translation, 1945 April 14; 11.5 x 15.5 (Box 1, Object 8006)
  - D70a: Certificate of presentation of medal: O Centro De Medicina Nuclear; Written in Portugese, 1960 March 11; Mounted; 11 x14.5 (Box 1, Object 8007)
  - D67: Certificate of appreciation: The Soil Science Center of the Philippines, 1957 December 22; Mounted; 11.5 x 15.5 (Box 1, Object 8008)
  - D115: Citation: Biosciences Information Service of Biological Abstracts, 1967 October 26; 10.5 x 13.5 (Box 1, Object 8009)
  - 84: Certificate: American Hungarian Studies Foundation and Hungarian University Association, Inc, 1963 December 10; Mounted; 13 x 15 (Box 1, Object 8010)
  - 58: Textile: Embroidery from the Former Fellows in Lebanon, 1955; 18 x 19 (Box 1, Object 8011)
    Commemorative
  - D111(D2): Golden medal of honor certificate: University of Vienna; Includes translation, 1922 May; 11 x 13 (Box 1, Object 8012)
  - D80b: Certificate: Nobel Foundation; Stockholm, 1963 April 2; 10 x 13.5 (Box 1, Object 8013)
  - D54: Diploma of Honor: El Presidente De la Republica De Columbia, 1954; Mounted; 11 x 16 (Box 1, Object 8014)
  - D68b: Certificate: St. Luke Nursing University; Includes translation, 1970 October 10; Mounted; 13.5 x 18.5 (Box 1, Object 8015)
  - D101a: Certificate: St. Luke Nursing University; Includes translation, 1970 October 10; Mounted; 13.5 x 18.5 (Box 1, Object 8016)
  - 74a: Certificate: Hokkaido University; Written in Japanese; Translated testimonial and copy, 1960 September 15; 8.5 x 11 (Box 1, Object 8017)
  - 74: Catalogue description of music box: Hokkaido University; Translated testimonial and copy, 1960 September 15; 8.5 x 11 (Box 1, Object 8018)
    Memorial
  - 77: Testimonial description of album: Deep Sea Researchers by Ryofu-maru", President of Nihon Oceanographic Society testimonial and copy, 1961 November 8; 8.5 x 11 (Box 1, Object 8019)
  - D122a:: Letter of Condolence on Mr. Rockefeller's death, From Keio University, undated; 3.5 x 9 (Box 1, Object 8020)
    Correspondence
  - 88:: Copy of certificate; Testimonial and copy, 1965 June 12; 8.5 x 11 (Box 1, Object 8021)
  - 73a: Letter of thanks (translation): Letter and copy from Seishichi Ohno of Sapporo Medical College, 1960 July 8; 8.5 x 11 (Box 1, Object 8022)
  - D68a: Letter of appreciation: Korean Language Research Society, 1958 April 24; Mounted; 12 x 16 (Box 1, Object 8028)
    Certificate
  - D102: Owen Staples etching: Doorway, School of Hygiene University of Toronto, undated; Mounted; 12 x15 (Box 1, Object 8029)
    Picture
  - D30: Photograph of plaque: Image of Max Planckk Institute, 1939 February 20; 4 x 6 (postcard). Two letters attached to postcard. (Box 1, Object 8030)
    Photograph
  - D123: Certificate of election:, 1975 May 13; Letter from Douglas Dillon attached; 10 x 13 (Box 1, Object 8031)
  - D97: Letter of congratulations: Catholic University of Louvain, 1963 April 2; Enclosed in folder with ribbon and tissue paper; 12 x 16 (Box 1, Object 8032)
  - D96: Diploma of honor, undated; Mounted; 14 x 19.5 (Box 1, Object 8033)
  - D34: Certificate: La Universidad de Guadalajara, 1943 October 15; Curling on right side; 15 x 19 (Box 1, Object 8034)
  - D112: Image of certificate: Emmett I. Vaughn, 1923 May; Mounted; 9 x 11 (Box 1, Object 8035)
  - D117: Diploma of honor: Masarykova Akademie Prace, 1921 (Box 1, Object 8036)
  - D116: Letter of welcome (Cloth): Rampur Ghori Health League Partabgarh Health Unit, India, 1937 April 23; Silk freying at edges; 11.5 x 16 (Box 1, Object 8037)
    Textile
  - D32: Certificate of merit: United States Public Health Service, 1942 September 15; Mounted with seal; 11 x 13.5 (Box 1, Object 8038)
  - D62: Honorary award: Institute of Logopedics, 1956 July 11; Mounted; 10 x 12 (Box 1, Object 8039)
  - D113: Certificate of special merit: New York Employing Printers Association, Inc., 1957 January 15-17; Mounted; 12 x 15.5 (Box 1, Object 8040)
  - D114: Certificate of special merit: Printing Industries of Metropolitan New York, Inc.; "For 1962 Annual Report", 1957 January 15-17; Mounted; 12.5 x 16.5 (Box 1, Object 8041)
  - D110: Diploma: Estados Unidos do Brasil; Mounted, undated; Mounted; 13.5 x 16 (Box 1, Object 8042)
  - D60: Diploma: Turk Devrim Tarihi Enstitusu; Written in Turkish, undated; Mounted; 14 x 17 (Box 1, Object 8043)
  - D78a: Certificate of participation: Film Festival of Agriculture; U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1962; Mounted; 12.5 x 16 (Box 1, Object 8044)
  - D31: Certificate: Board of Directors of The New York World's Fair 1939, 1940 January 6; Mounted; 15.5 x 18 (Box 1, Object 8045)
  - 57b: Flag: Flag of the Principality of Monaco, 1955 May 18; 38 x 50 (Box 2, Object 8046)
  - 101: Book: St. Luke Nursing University, 1970; 8 x 8.5 (Box 2, Object 8047)
  - Unknown: Award: The Lasker Group Award; Bound, 1950; 9.5 x 12 (Box 2, Object 8048)
  - 98: Certificate: The Graduate Institute of International Studies, 1963 April 2; Bound, 10 x 13.5 (Box 2, Object 8049)
  - D118: Bound certificate of appreciation: United Negro College Fund, undated; Bound, 9 x 12 (Box 2, Object 8050)
  - 40: Bound testimony: The Free University of Brussels; Written in latin; Includes letter of translation, 1946 March 12; Leatherbound in splicase, 7 x 11 (Box 2, Object 8051)
  - 86: Bound document: Includes "Statute of the Carl Zeiss Stiftung In Jena" booklet, Leatherbound in slipcase; 13 x 15 (Box 2, Object 8052)
  - 83: Model ship: Thai Library Association, undated; glass encased, 19.5 x 10 x 7 (Object 8053)
  - D20: Scroll container: Empty, 1933; 2 x 13.5 (Box 3, Object 8054)
    Contents placed in C1 and D1.
  - D124: Plaque: Inscribed "Student of Disease Theobald Smith 1859-1934", undated; 8.5 x 8.5 (Box 3, Object 8055)
  - D26:: Hommage Reconnaissant, undated; Bound with cutout pages containing ephemera, 8 x 10 (Box 3, Object 8056)
  - D29: Box: Contains stamps only, 1937 November 30; 7 x 9 x 2.5 (Box 17, Object 8057)
  - D72: Plaque: National University of Colombia, 1959 November 26; 6.5 x 8 (Box 3, Object 8058)
  - D80: Medal: Nobel Foundation, 1963 April 2; Silver, In box; 4 x 4 (Box 4, Object 8059)
  - D125: Medal, 1976 October 17; In box; 4 x 4 (Box 4, Object 8060)
  - D16: Medal, undated; In box; 3 x 4 (Box 4, Object 8061)
  - D38: Medal, undated; Bronze; Cardboard sleeve 4 x 5 (Box 4, Object 8062)
  - D6: Medal, undated; Bronze; Cardboard enclosure; Clasp on back; 4 x 4.5 (Box 4, Object 8063)
  - D100: Plaque: Instituto Nacional De Cardiologia; Written in Spanish, 1969 October; Felt box (Box 4, Object 8064)
  - T9: Seal: RF seal used by field staff in Cairo, undated (Box 4, Object 8065A)
  - T9: Stamper, undated; 3 x 9 (Box 4, Object 8065B)
  - D19b: Medal, 1927; In cardboard enclosure; 2.5 x 4 (Box 4, Object 8066)
  - D103: Medal, 1970; Bronze; In box; 3 x 3 (Box 4, Object 8067)
  - D69: Medal, 1959 October; Silver; In box; 3 x 3 (Box 4, Object 8068)
  - D37: Medal, undated; Bronze; In cardboard sleeve; 4 x4 (Box 4, Object 8069)
  - D85a: Medal: Johns Hopkins Hospital 50th Anniversary, 1964 May 14; Silver; In box; Doublesided; 4 x 4 (Box 4, Object 8070)
  - D43: Medal: Princeton University, 1947 June; Bronze; In box; (Box 4, Object 8071)
  - D56: Medal: Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith America's Legacy Award, 1955 May 11; Silver; In box; 5 x 5.5 (Box 4, Object 8072)
  - D87: Medal: Ninth International Grasslands Conference, 1965; 4 x 5 (Box 4, Object 8073)
  - D119: Medal: Educational Film Library Association-American Film Festival; Blue Ribbon Award-"Harvest", 1962; Encased in plastic (Box 4, Object 8074)
  - D120: Medal: Encased in plastic; Educational Film Library Association-American Film Festival; Blue Ribbon Award-"Rice", 1964; Encased in plastic (Box 4, Object 8075)
  - D86b: Paper document: Citation of Honor; Johns Hopkins Hospital, undated; In archival folder (Box 5, Object 8076)
  - D139: Paper document: Testimonio de Agradecimiento; Written in Spanish, 1977 August; Written in Spanish; Testimonio de Agradecimiento; In archival folder (Box 5, Object 8077)
  - D140: Paper document: Testimonio de Agradecimiento; Presented to RF; Written in Spanish, 1977 August; In archival folder (Box 5, Object 8078)
  - D142: Paper document: The Greater New York Fund Bronze Merit Award, 1966; In archival folder (Box 5, Object 8079)
  - D147: Paper document: Federal Republic of Brazil Ministry of Education and Culture, 1983 June 1; Green certificate holder; Includes typewritten note; In archival folder (Box 5, Object 8080)
  - Document holder, undated; Color illustrated; In archival folder (Box 5, Object 8081)
    Hardcover document holder
  - D146: Postage stamps, 1983 October 10; Torn along back; Framed; 13 x 15 (Box 6, Object 8082)
  - D164: Certificate, 1987 June 22; Framed; Includes paper describing item; 14 x 17.5 (Box 6, Object 8083)
  - D162: Proclamation: National Proclamation Day-Ronald Reagan; Includes letter from Frederick J. Ryan Jr., 1987 January 14; Embossed with seal; In envelope; 10 x 14.5 (Box 6, Object 8084)
  - D163: Certificate: New York Public Library Schomburg Society for the Preservation of Black Culture, In archival folder; 9 x 12 (Box 6, Object 8085)
  - D21: Scroll: Written in Arabic, 1933 December 15; Double-sided; Painted frame; 10 x 13.5 (Box 7, Object 8086)
  - D91: Scroll: Written in Spanish; Includes type-written translation on back of frame, 1968; Framed; 14 x 19 (Box 7, Object 8087)
  - D161: Plaque: International Rice Research Institute, 1986 October 15; In box (Box 7, Object 8088)
  - Unknown: Plaque: 55th Anniversary Metropolitan Insurance Company, 1979 January 1; 11 x 14 (Box 7, Object 8089)
  - D160: Medal: Semicentennial of the Pontifica Universidad Javeriana, Colombia, In blue box (Box 7, Object 8090)
  - D159: Plaque: Tufts University; Includes copy of letter from Craig L. Pritchard, 1985 August 22; 10 x 12 (Box 7, Object 8091)
  - D128: Plaque: India League of America, 1974; 10 x 14 (Box 8, Object 8092)
  - D137: Award, 1979 March 23; Framed; 12 x 17 (Box 8, Object 8093)
  - D177: Award booklet: Montblanc de la Culture; Includes newspaper clipping, 1992 April 21; 7 x 10 (Box 9, Object 8094)
  - D179: Booklet of caricatures: Al Hirschfeld drawing; 18/100; Montblanc De La Culture: The 1992 Jury of Artists (Box 9, Object 8095A)
  - D179: Booklet of caricatures: Al Hirschfeld drawing; 69/100; Montblanc De La Culture: The 1992 Jury of Artists (Box 9, Object 8095B)
  - D179: Booklet of caricatures: Al Hirschfeld drawing; Montblanc De La Culture: The 1992 Jury of Artists (Box 9, Object 8095C)
  - D180: Medal and Certificate: Includes copies of letters., 1994 April 26 (Box 9, Object 8096)
  - D181: Plaque: New Horizon Award-Crossroads Theatre Company, 1998 November 13; 10 x 13 (Box 9, Object 8097)
  - D132: Plaque: Kasetsart University, 8 x 10 (Box 10, Object 8098)
  - D127: Plaque: Universidad Nacional Agraria, 9 x 11 (Box 10, Object 8099)
  - D148: Triticale (Wheat): Mexican grown, Framed; 8 x 12 (Box 11, Object 8100)
  - D149: Plaque: International Rice Research Institute 20th Anniversary, 1980; 10 x 12 (Box 11, Object 8101)
  - D174: Plaque: International Hispanic Theatre Festival, 1990; 4 x 6 (Box 11, Object 8102A)
  - D174: Award: International Hispanic Theatre Festival, 1991; 5 x 7 (Box 11, Object 8102B)
  - D174: Award: International Hispanic Theatre Festival, 1992; 3 x 4 (Box 11, Object 8102C)
  - D176: Book, Bound book; 9 x 12 (Box 12, Object 8103A)
  - D176: Clock, 1993; In box; Photos and copy of letter separated (Box 12, Object 8103B)
  - D175: Certificate: Johns Hopkins University School of Hygiene Public Health Dean's Appreciation Award; Copy of letter attached, 1992 August 23; 15 x 17 (Box 12, Object 8104)
  - D136: Plaque: Society of Builders for the Future University of Minnesota, 11 x 14 (Box 13, Object 8105)
  - D106: Plaque: American Phytopathological Society, 1972 August 10; 12 x 14 (Box 13, Object 8106)
    Testimonial
  - D170: Award: Arts & Business Council, Inc., 3 x 10 (Box 14, Object 8107)
  - D168: Plaque: Metropolitan Life Sixty-Fifth Anniversary, 1989 January 1; Brass and wood; In box; Includes letter; 3.5 x 5 (Box 14, Object 8108)
  - D171: Book: Universidad De Los Andes, Separated letter in archival folder; 10 x 13 (Box 14, Object 8109A)
  - D171: Certificate: Universidad De Los Andes, Colombia 40th Anniverary, 1988 November 16 (Box 14, Object 8109B)
  - D169: Award: Television Critics Association Outstanding Achievement, 1987 (Box 14, Object 8110)
  - D167: Artwork: Gift from Bao Ke Ming, 1989 June 6; Framed (Box 14, Object 8111)
    Miscellaneous
  - D151: Photograph: RF Agricultural Sciences Staff Seminar, 1979 November; Framed (Box 15, Object 8112)
  - D155: Award: University of Tennessee Benefactors Society, 1982; In box; 5 x 7 (Box 15, Object 8113)
  - D150: Metal plate: College of Veterinary Medicine Michigan State University Dean's Club, 6 x 12 (Box 15, Object 8114)
  - D165: Photograph: Photo of Princess Chulabhorn of Thailand; includes letter., 1988 July 31; Leather framed, 10 x 13 (Box 15, Object 8115)
  - D130: Artwork: New Perspectives Award, 1979; Framed; Leather enclosure on back with newspaper clipping; 12 x 14; (Box 8, Object 8116)
  - D156: Plaque: Tenth Thai National Corn and Sorghum Reporting Session, Metal unattached to backing; 9 x 11.5 (Box 16, Object 8117)
  - D157: Award: Institute of Food and Agricultural Sciences at the University of Florida, 1984; 11 x 12.5 (Box 16, Object 8118)
  - D152: Certificate, 1980 November; Framed; 11 x 15 (Box 16, Object 8119)
  - D158: Artwork: Watercolor painiting; Cover written in French, 12 x 16 (Box 16, Object 8120)
  - D141: Bowl: Brass, Two parts (Box 17, Object 8121)
  - D45: Certificate: Certificate and holder; University of Copenhagen, 1947 May (Box 18, Object 8122)
  - Textile, Red and gold (Box 18, Object 8123)
  - D79: Blanket, 1978 June 21; Woolen blanket (Box 19, Object 8124)
  - D131: Plaque, 1979 January; Gold tone on black base; 7.5 x 10 (Box 20, Object 8125)
  - D143: Plaque, 1981 February 10; 10 x 11 (Box 20, Object 8126)
  - D146: Plaque, 1983 October 10; Cracked along back; 6 x 8 (Box 20, Object 8127)
  - D134: Plaque, 1970 December 31; 10 x 14 (Box 20, Object 8128)
  - D129: Plaque: Bronze, 1978 June 21; In commemorative wooden box; 11 x 15 (Box 20, Object 8129)
  - D77a: Album, Hardcover; Decorative; 12 x 13 (Box 20, Object 8130)
  - D145: Medallion: Bronze, 1982 December; In box; 4 x 5 (Box 20, Object 8131)
  - D191: Book: Princeton University The First 250 Years, by Don Oberdorfer, In box sleeve; 9 x 13 (Box 21, Object 8132)
    Book
  - D192: Award: Independent Sector, In box; 8 x 10 (Box 21, Object 8133)
  - Award: Photo of H.R.H. sultan Hamengku Buwono X, In lined box; 7 x 9 (Box 21, Object 8134)
  - D184: Plate: Instiute of American Indian Arts; Plate no. 29, Red, gold, and white (Box 21, Object 8135)
  - D194: Medal: The Sir Harold Acton Medal of New York University, In box; 4.5 x 7 (Box 21, Object 8136)
  - D188: Paperweight: OPERA America award, 1988 December 9; OPERA America award (Box 21, Object 8137)
  - D187: Medallion, Silver; In box; 3 x 3 (Box 21, Object 8138)
  - D189: Medal: Cal Arts' 25th Anniversary, 1995 May 5; In box; 4 x 4 (Box 21, Object 8139)
  - D185: Medal, In box; 4 x 4 (Box 21, Object 8140)
  - D186: Medallion, 1988; In box; 3.5 x 3.5 (Box 21, Object 8141)